

# ROBERT W. SCHUSTER

robertwschuster@gmail.com

+61 407 017 141

Brisbane, AUS



# **EDUCATION**

#### The University of Queensland

Brisbane, AUS

PhD - Biomechanics

10/2018 - 03/2023

• Thesis: Establishing the relationship between foot form and function

- Supervised by A/Prof Luke Kelly and Prof Andrew Cresswell
- Dean's Award for outstanding contribution to the discipline (nominated)

# **Technical University of Munich**

Munich, GER

**MSc - Diagnostics & Training** 

09/2014 - 09/2017

- Focus on applied biomechanics and exercise physiology testing
- *Thesis:* High-density electromyographic identification of neuromuscular determinants of drop jump performance across varying drop heights

# **Technical University of Munich**

Munich, GER

**BSc - Scientific Principles of Sports** 

09/2010 - 06/2014

 Thesis: Influence of electrical stimulation applied to the quadriceps femoris on height of a subsequent squat jump in context of postactivation potentiation

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Australian Catholic University**

Brisbane, AUS

**Research Assistant** 

05/2022 - 12/2022

- Biomechanics and data analysis support for various research projects
- Developed R shiny apps for the analysis of performance assessment and sleep tracking data

#### **VALD Performance**

Brisbane, AUS

**Industry Placement** 

05/2022 - 07/2022

 Explored combining load cell and IMU data for dynamic strength assessment with the DynaMo handheld dynamometer

#### The University of Queensland

Brisbane, AUS

**Graduate Teaching Assistant** 

07/2019 - 11/2021

- Taught Biomechanics
- Helped create online teaching material

#### Technical University of Munich

Munich, GER

Scientific Staff Member

08/2017 - 08/2018

- Department of Biomechanics in Sports (Prof Ansgar Schwirtz)
- Involved in various research projects with high performance (DSV) and industry partners (eGym & BMW)
- Taught Biomechanical Competencies and Methods in Kinesiology

#### Olympic Centre Bavaria

Munich, GER

**Performance Diagnostics** 

05/2016 - 08/2018

 Performed strength and speed diagnostics of national and international level athletes from various Olympic disciplines

#### Technical University of Munich

Munich, GER

**Student Assistant** 

05/2016 - 08/2017

- Department of Biomechanics in Sports (Prof Ansgar Schwirtz)
- Collected, processed and analysed data for a research project examining cross-country roller-ski skating technique of international level biathletes and cross-country skiers

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am naturally curious and enjoy the process of investigating challenging questions as well as solving complex problems.

0000-003-1738-7136

I have extensive experience collecting, processing, analysing and communicating research data, and have applied these skills across a wide range of fields concerned with human health and performance.

# SKILLS

# **Programming Languages**

R	
MATLAB	
Python	
GitHub	robertwschuster

# Data Acquisition and Analysis

3D motion captu	ıre	
Dynamometry		
Electromyography		
OpenSim		
Statistical modelling		

Beginner Intermediate Expert

#### LANGUAGES

GermanNativeEnglishNear nativeSpanishFluentFrenchBasic knowledge

#### SOCIETIES

Australian and New Zealand Society of Biomechanics

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

Playing rugby union, strength training, running, cooking, watching movies, and reading (mostly nonfiction/popular science)